Hamid Reza Asaadi

- www https://hr.asadi.github.io
- https://github.com/hrasadi
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hrasadi
- hr.asadi@gmail.com
- +1 (631) 590-0327

Summary

Versatile software engineer with 8+ years of experience in software development, enterprise software architecture and managing software teams and startups. Worked in a variety of domains (from banking systems to video broadcasting) with outstanding problem solving and analytical skills to completely understand the nature of the problem and finding affordable solutions at any level. Enthusiastic to improve the performance and productivity of teams and interested in both engineering challenges and human interactions.

Education

• PhD student in Computer Science, Stony Brook University, United States
o GPA: 4.0/4.0

• M.Sc in Software Engineering, University of Tehran, Iran

• B.Sc in Computer Engineering, University of Tehran, Iran

Sep. 2008 – Jun. 2010 Sep. 2004 – Jul. 2008

Core Qualifications

- Expert software developer and enterprise software architect
- Teaching and instructing (worked 4 academic years as K-12 teacher and 6 semesters as university TA)
- Team working and effective team management using Agile processes and techniques
- Presentation and speaking (invited speaker to 5 events, each targeted for a different type of audience)

Technical Skills

- Languages: Java (Expert), C++ (Skilled), Javascript (Skilled), Objective-C (Familiar), Swift (Familiar), Python (Familiar)
- Frameworks and Libraries: Play Framework, Spring, Angular JS, Hibernate
- Databases: mongoDB, MySQL, SQL Server
- Platforms and Operating Systems: Amazon Web Services (Administration), Linux (Expert), Windows (Skilled)
- Other Tools: Git, Atlassian Jira, Atlassian Confluence, ThoughtWorks Go, IntelliJ IDEA, Xcode, Visual Studio, Eclipse

Working Experiences

Radio Auto-asaad (Persian-speaking internet radio station)

Founder

May 2017 – Current

Radio Auto-asaad was first started as a hobby project with the goal of developing a fully automated radio station with live broadcasting capabilities. However, besides interesting technical offerings, it also successfully created a valuable community of producers, a large listener-base and fans all around the globe.

Nexeven AB (a Swedish company and a niche player in the online video broadcasting field)

Chief Technical Officer

Feb. 2014 – Aug. 2016

Delivered Nexeven Sense product to operational environment within less than a year time. Nexeven Sense agent system collects user data from more than 13 different platforms and provides online reports about quality of broadcasting.

Maxa Co. (a software quality engineering startup)

• Chairman

Jan. 2014 – Current

• Co-founder and CEO

Mar. 2011 – Jan. 2014

Managed the company since its foundation for two years. During this period, team grew to 20+ people and served more than 10 large and medium-size customers with software performance testing and analysis services.

Fanap Co. (IT subsidiary of Bank Pasargad of Iran, with the mission of developing banking solutions)

• Manager of Software Quality Lab

Dec. 2009 – Mar. 2011

Improved Fanap Card Management System (CMS) performance by more than 100% and resolved performance bottlenecks and deadlocks in all company's products by setting up the first specialized software testing team in a company of 100+ developers.

Hamgam IT Co. (Hamgam IT develops customized software for enterprises, using Model-Driven Design practices)

• Software Architect and Senior Developer

Feb. 2009 – Dec. 2009

• Software Developer

Mar. 2008 - Feb. 2009

Refactored and integrated new features in a ten-year old MDD framework and migrated it from .Net version 1.1 to .Net version 3.5, keeping it fully backward compatible with zero effort needed to migrate the existing code bases.